MICHAEL J. ANDERSON

Rancho Santa Margarita, CA, 92688 | **Phone**: (714)482-5401 | **Email**: mjanders6@gmail.com **Web**: https://www.mj-anderson.com | **LinkedIn**: www.linkedin.com/in/mjanders6 | **Github**: mjanders6

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Mechanical Engineering and project management. 5+ years experience in operations management. Excellent problem solver, collaborator and enjoys challenges to work within a team to tackle complex issues. Progressively looking to utilize the technical toolbox.

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine, CA | Full Stack Web Development | Coding Certificate

• A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

California State University, Los Angeles, CA | Masters of Science, Mechanical Engineering California State University, Los Angeles, CA | Bachelors of Science, Mechanical Engineering

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Node, React, MySQL, No-SQL, MongoDB, HTML5 & CSS, R, VBA. **Applications:** REST APIs, CRUD development, Heroku Deployment, Firebase Deployment, MERN Stack

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Super Street Battle: Github | Deployed

- Single-player RPG game designed to battle streetcars after carefully building and designing the car's performance.
- Role: Back-End Developer | Tools: MongoDB, No-SQL, Mongoose NPM, Heroku, Full MERN stack Porcelain: Github | Deployed
 - This app allows you to find bathrooms close to you. It allows the user to add comments and likes to the bathroom and submit a request to the admin to add new bathrooms.
 - **Role**: Git Master, setting up the overall structure, page linking, and Heroku app deployment. | **Tools**: Javascript, React, Express, Heroku, and MySQL

Pantry Project: Glthub | Deployed

- This app was designed to find recipes and if your too lazy to cook, or just don't want to, then you can search for restaurants around you.
- **Role**: Building the API to locate the restaurant given a location. Mapbox and Zomato were used together to locate the restaurant | **Tools**: Javascript, Mapbox API, Zomato API

EXPERIENCE

Warehouse Manager Express Pipe

2019 – Present Fontana. CA

- Managed 20+ direct reports, ensuring all orders are pulled and processed for deliveries while communicating all delivery time constraints in a timely manner, held daily huddles with the team to communicate pulling errors and success stories building team engagement.
- Successfully built and developed the warehouse team during the transition of becoming the main distribution center for the Inland Empire creating a strong structure and team cohesion.

Warehouse Manager

2018 - 2019

Multi Sales Inc.

La Palma, CA

Effectively stabilized receiving and distribution by hiring and developing key team members.

Warehouse and Ops. Manager Applied Medical

2013 - 2019

Rancho Santa Margarita, CA

• Managed 25+ direct and indirect reports between 3 warehouses. Ensured all orders are pulled and processed for deliveries while communicating all delivery time constraints in a timely manner.

- Utilized R and VBA to create specific reports for the inventory team to eliminate backorders. R was used
 to tidy up the data while VBA was used to help standardize what inventory to focus on in an easy to use
 format for the Inventory Supervisor.
- Effectively reduced the warehouse processing time by 50% through standardizing operations and processing areas.
- Designed and implemented a packing and shipping process for Europe manufacturing.
- Reduced the JIT warehouse by 20% to allow for storing higher demand inventory.
- Utilized pick reports from SAP to define a picking standard; utilized R to standardize the data sets while VBA and excel pivot tables were used for presentational purposes.